Come in
Входи
This old minister heard Your Majesty was hit by an arrow
Когда я услышал что Вас ранили стрелой
Was greatly alarmed
сердце моё сжалось от страха
Now seeing Your Majesty safe
Теперь увидев Вас в добром здравии
This old minister is at ease
я спокоен
This is Li Dingyuan's memorial
Вот доклад Ли Динъюаня
Your Majesty
Ваше Величество
Your servant has verified everything
Ваше Величество я всё тщательно проверил
The Xie family colluded with factions
Дом Се вступил в сговор с фракциями
Embezzled state taxes at every level
присваивая налоги на каждом этапе
Originally two hundred taels of silver
Из первоначальных двухсот лян серебра
When it reached the court
до казны
Only one hundred taels remained
доходила лишь половина
Take a look
Посмотри сам
You and I have been ruler and minister
Мы с тобой были император и слуга
Everyone has their own account in their heart
У каждого в сердце свои счёты
Others may not remember this bond
Другие могут забыть о прошлом
But I
но я
Cannot forget
не могу не помнить
These years
Эти годы
What you've done
что ты делал
You and I both understand in our hearts
и ты и я прекрасно знаем
False accusation
Клевета
These are all false accusations
Всё это ложь
Your Majesty
Ваше Величество
This old minister has followed Your Majesty since the second year of Yuankang
Я следую за Вашим Величеством со второго года эры Юанькан
This old minister has never had disloyal thoughts toward Your Majesty
У меня нет никаких дурных намерений к Вашему Величеству
I
Мне
Have little time left
осталось недолго
While I am here
Пока я жив
I can still tolerate you
я мог тебя защитить
When I'm gone
Но без меня
Xuan Kingdom
Сюань
Cannot tolerate you
не сможет тебя терпеть
Your servant
Я
Your servant is guilty
виновен
Your servant is ashamed before Your Majesty
Я недостоин Вашего Величества